SAIPRASAD RATHOD

rsaiprasad4+jobs@gmail.com | +919922499094 |1-15-1334, Banjara Nivas, Sharda Nagar, Nanded, Maharashtra, India - 431605. | https://www.linkedin.com/in/saiprasad-rathod-825a761a5/

SUMMARY

Full Stack MERN Software Developer with 2+ years of experience in developing scalable performance-oriented applications. Quickly adapting new technologies and writing quality code, working in an agile team with continuous delivery. Effective team players with exceptional planning and execution skills, tracking projects from initiation to delivery.

SKILLS

Programming Knowledge: Javascript.

Frameworks: Node.js, React.js. **Databases:** MongoDB, MySQL.

Tools And Platforms: VS Code, Git, GitHub, Firebase, Redis, AWS, Oracle.

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Mechanical Engineering,

ICEEM, Aurangabad High School (12th Grade), N.E.S. SCIENCE COLLEGE, Nanded Sep 2017 - May 2021 CGPA: 8.4 July 2016 - May 2017

EXPERIENCE

MERN Full Stack Developer, Stacklab.in, Pune

Apr 2023 - Present

- Acquired comprehensive skills in full stack development, focusing on React is for frontend and Node is for backend.
- Built web applications in MERN Stack with 7 diverse projects, integrating advanced features and functionalities.
- Developed chat applications using WebSockets, enhancing real-time communication capabilities.
- Implemented solutions on Oracle Cloud and firebase, ensuring scalable and efficient cloud services.
- Utilized Firebase for push notifications, cloud database management, and cloud messaging, improving app responsiveness and user engagement..

Backend Developer, FunctionUp (Fanplay Technologies), Bangalore

Mar 2022 - Feb 2023

- Trained in backend development using Node.js with Express and MongoDB..
- Understands Caching Fundamentals and hands-on experience with redis.
- Understands the way of writing clean code with no errors.
- Hands-on experience with AWS S3 file upload and reading.
- Experienced in Agile Methodology Daily Scrum, Sprint Planning, Sprint Review.
- Participated in various coding competitions organized by functionUp on platforms such as HackerRank and CodeZinger.

PROJECTS

Accounting Software

- Designed and led the end-to-end development of the software.
- Designed and implemented core modules such as Authentication, Customer, Vendor, Employee Masters, Product Masters.
- Conducted comprehensive testing and debugging to ensure system reliability.
- Utilized SendGrid for email delivery integration.

Tracking Software

- Led the full software development lifecycle, from requirements gathering to deployment and maintenance.
- Designed and implemented the job card management and shipment tracking modules.
- Developed and integrated the functionality for generating docket stickers for domestic shipments.

Standard Operating Procedures

- Developed a web app in React.Js for printing firms.
- It aims to streamline Standard Operating Procedure (SOP) creation process for employees within the printing solutions industry.
- This system facilitates job creation, assignment, and tracking, inventory management, integrating role-based access control for efficient management.

Loyali (Shopping App in Australia)

- Constructed an e-commerce website designed to showcase the entire product catalog, aiming to optimize business sales.
- Implemented database sessions to manage and maintain user interactions across the project.
- The Loyali App was created to address the demand for a contemporary, efficient, cost-free, and user-friendly loyalty program.
- Improved performance of the application by using background services, async tasks, etc.

ATROS (Aqua Tech RO Systems Pvt. Ltd.)

- Designed and developed a web application for efficiently managing RO Devices and their dependencies at ATROS.
- Optimized core modules such as user, device, subscription, and task management, ensuring efficient role-based access, automation, and real-time tracking for technicians' assignments.
- Integrated features such as RO device recharging, recharge-based disbursement, and usage-based billing directly on the website.